A Guide to the Virginia Dept. of General Services Plans, Reports and Feasibility Studies, 1987-1994
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Dept. of General Services Plans, Reports and Feasibility Studies, 1987-1994
The Library of Virginia
43693
1.5 cu. ft (5 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Wendell Seldon, formerly of the Virginia Dept. of General Services, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, 3 October 2007.
Biographical Information
The mission of the Dept. of General Services is to provide supportive services to other state agencies, local political subdivisions as appropriate, in the areas of laboratory services; maintenance, operation and construction of facilities; land management; land and facilities acquisition; disposal and sale of material and supplies; risk management; and other related activities. The Commission on State Governmental Management recommended the creation of the Dept. of General Services to be comprised of the then existing Dept. of Purchases and Supplies, Division of Engineering and Buildings, Division of Consolidated Laboratory Services, Dept. of Property Records and Insurance, and several other state agencies functions which were subsequently determined by appropriate authorities to be left outside of the organization of this department. In 1976, the General Assembly passed H.B. 1240 which called for the establishment of the position of a director of the department and required the appointee to prepare a plan for the organization of this department with implementing legislation. This was accomplished and the 1977 session of the General Assembly enacted Chapter 672 which created the Dept. of General Services. Consistent with this statute, the department was officially implemented on July 1, 1978.
Major activities of the department are to maintain and operate facilities at the seat of government; assist in the administration of the capital outlay budget of the Commonwealth; to assist in acquisition of real property either by lease or purchase; to perform centralized purchasing functions of the Commonwealth; to dispose of surplus real property and material and supplies; to provide a comprehensive risk management insurance program for all agencies and institutions; to operate a centralized purchasing and warehousing function for supplying State agencies and certain political subdivisions with equipment and supplies; to acquire or provide printing services for State agencies and institutions; provide central mail and messenger service for State agencies in the area of the seat of government; provide laboratory research and scientific services in the area of environmental sciences; forensic science, microbiology, and product regulation; to provide training to law enforcement personnel in the collection and preservation of evidence; and to conduct programs on inspection and certification of certain laboratories through the state.
Scope and Content
Contains a variety of plans, reports, and feasibility studies pertaining to state buildings and projects. Some of the material was created by state agencies other than the Dept. of General Services. Items of note included in this collection are reports and plans pertaining to the Virginia State Library and Archives and the Virginia Public Safety Complex (Elko Tract), reports of the Joint Audit and Review Commission, several strategic plans produced by Governor L. Douglas Wilder's office, and a Historic American Buildings Survey of Virginia's State Capitol.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into one series:
Series I. Plans, Reports and Feasibility Studies, 1987-1994
The material is arranged alphabetically by title. All oversize material is located in Box 5.
Contents List
- Series I. Plans, Reports and Feasibility Studies, 1987-1994. (Box 1-5.)
  - Blue Ribbon Strike Force, Governor's Commission on Government Reform Summary of Recommendations, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Blue Ribbon Strike Force, Governor's Commission on Government Reform Summary of Recommendations, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Blue Ribbon Strike Force, Governor's Commission on Government Reform Summary of Recommendations, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Blue Ribbon Strike Force, Governor's Commission on Government Reform Summary of Recommendations, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Blue Ribbon Strike Force, Governor's Commission on Government Reform Summary of Recommendations, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Capitol Square Complex and Broad Street Station Site Master Plan and Study Report, 1991. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Capitol Square Complex and Broad Street Station Site Master Plan and Study Report, 1991. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Capitol Square Complex and Broad Street Station Site Master Plan and Study Report, 1991. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Commission on Prison and Jail Overcrowding Report, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Condition of the Commonwealth and Executive Budget Recommendations, 1988-1990. (Box 5)
  - Condition of the Commonwealth and Executive Budget Recommendations, 1990-1992. (Box 5)
  - Elko Tract Proposed Master Plan, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Elko Tract Proposed Master Plan, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Governor L. Douglas Wilder's Agenda for Virginia (copy 1), undated. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Governor L. Douglas Wilder's Agenda for Virginia (copy 2), undated. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Governor L. Douglas Wilder's Drug Control Strategy, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Governor L. Douglas Wilder's Strategic Plan for Rural Development, undated. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Historic American Buildings Survey: Virginia State Capitol, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Historic American Buildings Survey: Virginia State Capitol, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Historic American Buildings Survey: Virginia State Capitol, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Historic American Buildings Survey: Virginia State Capitol, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Historic American Buildings Survey: Virginia State Capitol, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Historic American Buildings Survey: Virginia State Capitol, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Historic American Buildings Survey: Virginia State Capitol, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Historic American Buildings Survey: Virginia State Capitol, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission Report to the General Assembly, 1987. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission Report to the General Assembly, 1989. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission Report to the General Assembly, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Report on the Future of the Capital Area, 2000/2010, Vol. 1, undated. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Report on the Future of the Capital Area, 2000/2010, Vol. 2, undated. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - State Agency Planning Guidelines for the Collection and Marketing of Recyclable Materials, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Public Safety Complex (Elko Tract) Preplanning Study, 1988. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Public Safety Complex (Elko Tract) Preplanning Study, 1988. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Public Safety Complex (Elko Tract) Preplanning Study, 1988. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Public Safety Complex (Elko Tract) Preplanning Study, 1988. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Public Safety Complex (Elko Tract) Preplanning Study, 1988. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Public Safety Complex (Elko Tract) Preplanning Study, 1988. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Public Safety Complex (Elko Tract) Preplanning Study, 1988. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Virginia State Library and Archives Feasibility Study, 1987. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Virginia State Library and Archives Feasibility Study, 1987. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Virginia State Library and Archives, Planning Issues Study for, 1989. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Virginia State Library and Archives, Planning Issues Study for, 1989. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Virginia State Library and Archives Preplanning Study, 1989. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Virginia State Library and Archives Preplanning Study, 1989. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Virginia State Library and Archives Proposal (Glave Newman Anderson Architects and Skidmore, Owings and Merrill), 1991. (Box 5)